neworleanssaints.com 2012-12-31

# New Orleans Saints | Privacy Policy

New Orleans Saints Website Privacy Policy (Last Updated: 5/30/12)

This privacy policy applies to the NewOrleansSaints' website located at www.NewOrleansSaints.com (the "Website"). The purpose of this privacy policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.

The Website is operated by Cypress Consulting on behalf of the New Orleans Saints (collectively, the "Saints", "we", "our", or "us"). Cypress Consulting does not own any information submitted through this website and cannot use this information for its own purposes.

New Orleans Saints has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers information collected through this Web site, www.NewOrleansSaints.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at (504) 733-0255.If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe [here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

The New Orleans Saints complies with the U.S. – E.U.  Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the from European Union member countries.  The New Orleans Saints have certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view New Orleans Saints certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

When this privacy policy uses the term "personally identifiable information" or "personal information," we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as your full name, street address or email address. When other information, such as a favorite team or player, is associated with personal information, it also becomes personally identifiable information for the purposes of this privacy policy.

Please read the information below to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.

  1. [Types of Information That May be Collected](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#TypesOfInformation)
  2. [How Information May be Collected](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#HowInfoCollected)
  3. [How We Use the Information Collected ](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#HowWeUse)
  4. [With Whom the Information May be Shared](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#WhomWeShare)
  5. [Security](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#Security)
  6. [Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#MessageBoards)
  7. [Links to Other Websites](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#LinksToOtherSites)
  8. [A Special Note for Parents Concerning Privacy](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#Parents)
  9. [Notification of Changes and Your Acceptance of the Privacy Policy](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#Acceptance)
  10. [Correcting/Updating Personal Information](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#Correcting)
  11. [Your California Privacy Rights](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#California)
  12. [Questions About This Privacy Policy](http://www.neworleanssaints.com/footer/privacy-policy.html#Questions)

Types of Information That May be Collected

The following are the types of information we may collect:

Information You Provide Us: In the course of using the website, we may ask you to provide us with certain information, including contact information, such as your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, or fax number, unique identifiers, such as your user password, demographic information, such as your date of birth, age, gender, ticket holder status or similar information (such as a friend's email address when forwarding an article from the site by e-mail -- This is a ONE TIME email and the data is not collected or stored by the site, so it cannot be used for further communications by the site.

Site Usage Information: We may receive and store certain types of internet usage information whenever you visit the Website, such as your click-stream data and your IP address.

Email Communications: When you open emails from us, we may receive a confirmation noting you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of what emails we send you and what emails you may be receiving from our subsidiaries and affiliates. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have opted to receive or not to receive.

* * *

How Information May be Collected

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:

Registration: You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer, such as newsletters or contests. Participation in registration is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

Newsletters and Website Emails: We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Website, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Website. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. You may also cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Website or in the newsletter or email or by emailing the club at comments@saints.nfl.com.

Contests or Sweepstakes: We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes, (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used). We may also ask your permission to allow us to publicly post some of your information on the Website, such as on a winner's page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Website, and collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we do not collect your information and we have no control over the information collected from you. Accordingly, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.

Surveys or Voting: From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

Games: When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information.

Cookies: As with many Websites, our Website uses a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a unique, random number that is stored in the browser on your computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify you, just the computer that is used to visit the site. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit the Website. Cookies also let us know how many people visit our website and where visitors go on the site. In addition, cookies can let us know non-personally identifiable information, like what web browser is being used to access the website. For registered users, cookies can make using the Website easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Website, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Website are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Website. Cookies may also allow the Website to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Website, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. Cookies ARE NOT tied to personal information.

Third Party Cookies: The use of cookies by our [partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers] is/is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do/do not have access or control over these cookies.  Our [partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers] use session ID cookies [to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.]   

Web beacons : Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data: We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information. Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request Web pages from the Website. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.

* * *

How We Use the Information Collected

As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used to:

  * contact you about the Website;
  * contact you relating to your membership status;
  * inform you of a prize you have won;
  * monitor or improve the use of the Website;
  * customize the advertising and content you see;
  * monitor compliance with our terms and conditions of use of the Website; and
  * send you promotional material or special offers on behalf of our marketing partners and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties.

* * *

With Whom the Information May be Shared

At times, we may share your personal information with others for various purposes. The following outlines the ways in which your information may be shared with others and the ways in which you may opt-out of having your information shared:

Agents: We employ other businesses, certain services and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Website analysis, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They may have access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for their own purposes, like sending you marketing offers about their products.

Third-party sites linked to by NewOrleansSaints.com are:   
www.neworleanssaintsteamshop.com (Official Internet Team Store)   
https://oss.ticketmaster.com/html/home.htmI?team=saints&l=EN&STAGE=1 (Ticketmaster Ticket Account Manager)   
http://saints.ed4.net/profile/index.cfm/saints/signup.html (E-Dialog Saints Now E-Newsletter Signup) 

The user is submitting their information directly to the third party, even though the pages have the look and feel of the team site. The privacy policy of the third party (NewOrleansSaintsTeamShop, Ticketmaster and E-Dialog) applies to their respective sites.

Aggregate Information: We may share aggregate information, such as demographics and Website usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors or other organizations. When this type of information is shared, the other parties do not have access to your personally identifiable information.

Other Promotional Offers: We may send offers to you on behalf of our marketing partners. When we do this, we do not give that partner your name and address. If you do not want to receive such offers, you may use the opt out method detailed in the email or change your preferences by logging into your account.

Audience and Traffic Measurement Services: Audience and Traffic Measurement Services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from our Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Website cookies, the Website's traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.

Business Transfers: In the event that all or substantially all of our assets are sold or transferred to another party, or another transaction occurs in which your personally identifiable information is one of the business assets transferred, all personally identifiable information that has been collected and saved may be one of the business assets we transfer. **Please refer to "Your acceptance of the privacy policy and notification of changes to the policy" section below.  
**  
Administrative or Legal Process: Your personal information may be transferred to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, law enforcement agencies, to protect our rights, or protect the rights of other users of this website.

* * *

Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards

The Website may make chat rooms, forums and message boards available to its users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas.

* * *

Links to Other Websites

You should be aware that when you are on the Website you could be directed to other Websites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Website onto a different Website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and marketing partners that may use the Website's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other Websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a Website that is linked to our Website, you should consult that Website's privacy policy before providing any personal information.

* * *

Security

This Website incorporates reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information that we may collect and we have put into place reasonable precautions to protect such information from loss, misuse and alteration. Your personally identifiable information is transferred to our computers utilizing encryption software. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised as required.

* * *

A Special Note for Parents Concerning Privacy

The Website is a general audience Website. We do not currently collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the Website. If in the future, we collect personally identifiable information from children, it will do so in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (15 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.) including, without limitation, obtaining necessary parental consent. For more information about the privacy practices for our affiliated children's Website, www.PlayFootball.com, please consult the privacy policy at the children's Website.

The Internet offers children wonderful educational and entertainment resources. Your guidance and involvement are essential to help ensure that children have a safe and rewarding online experience. We encourage you to visit the Direct Marketing Association's Web Website (www.the-dma.org) and explore the Get CyberSavvy! Program as well as the GetNetWise Website (www.getnetwise.org) to learn more about parental control tools.

* * *

Your Acceptance of the Privacy Policy and Notification of Changes to the Policy

By using this Website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on our website and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address. We will assume that you have given your permission for your information to be used under the terms of the new privacy policy, if you do not respond to our email within thirty days or continue to use the Website thirty days after a notice is posted. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.

* * *

Correcting/Updating Personal Information

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your email address or zip code), or if you no longer desire to access our Website, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update, delete or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by making changes to your profile, by using an opt-out message in an email, or by emailing us at comments@saints.nfl.com. We will respond to your request within 10-20 business days.

* * *

Data Retention: We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [email address].  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  

Your California Privacy Rights

A California privacy law that went into effect on January 1, 2005, allows California residents to obtain specific information about a business's privacy practices if it shares information with other companies for those companies' direct marketing purposes.

As explained in this privacy policy, whenever you agree to let us collect personal information about you, we will always provide you with an option to prevent this information from being shared for non-administrative purposes with third parties. You can exercise this option at any time by following the steps outlined above.

Because this website has a comprehensive privacy policy and provides you with details on how you may opt-in/opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes, we are not required to provide you with this information.

If you are a California resident and have questions about our compliance with this law, please send an email to comments@saints.nfl.com or write to us at CA Privacy Rights, New Orleans Saints, 5800 Airline Drive; Metairie, LA 70003.

* * *

Questions about this Privacy Policy

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the privacy practices of this Website, contact comments@saints.nfl.com.

**Questions regarding this statement should be directed to:  
New Orleans Saints, 5800 Airline Drive; Metairie, LA 70003   
Attn: Website Privacy Policy   
**
